## Jermaine Blake

### **Software Developer**

PHONE	EMAIL	ADDRESS	LINKEDIN	
(416) 624-4220	info@jermaineblake.dev	Toronto, ON	<u>LinkedIn</u>	

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software developer passionate and enthusiastic about learning and building purposeful applications backed by over 10 years of success across multiple business roles and a strong understanding of the full customer experience.

#### **PERSONAL PORTFOLIO & REPOSITORIES**

jermaineblake.dev

**GitHub** 

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

1	Design	1	Communication	1	<b>Process Improvement</b>
---	--------	---	---------------	---	----------------------------

✓ Full-Stack Software Design & 
✓ Problem Solving
✓ Adaptability

Coding

✓ Data Analysis
✓ Cross-Functional Engagement
✓ Collaboration

#### **TECHNICAL COMPETENCIES**

✓ RESTful APIs ✓ JavaScript ✓ N	Node.js
---------------------------------	---------

✓ SQL, NoSQL databases
✓ Python
✓ Django

✓ React
✓ Express
✓ Mongoose

✓ HTML5
✓ CSS & SaSS
✓ Agile

✓ MVC Framework
✓ Git/GitHub (version control)
✓ OOP

Jermaine is excellent at following through on tasks to make sure they are completed. Jermaine thinks through the different scenarios and possibilities to come up with a reasonable, well thought out solution.

#### Stuart Bustard, Area Manager, Enterprise Rent-a-Car

#### **EDUCATION**

Certificate of Completion, General Assembly, Toronto Sept 2020 - Dec 2020 450+ hours, Software Engineering Immersive Program

Bachelor of Science, University of Guelph

Major, Biological Science, Graduated with Honours.

Sept 2006 – May 2011

Varsity football team member

## **Jermaine Blake**

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY TORONTO**, Toronto, ON

Sept 2020 – Dec 2020

General Assembly is a pioneer in education and career transformation, specializing in today's most in-demand skills.

#### **Software Developer**

- Built full-stack web applications using Node.js, Express, MongoDB, React, PostgreSQL, Django technologies.
- Collaborated on a real-time, multiplayer, trivia application. Managed gitflow workflow for application by using branches for new features. Reviewed dozens of pull requests to ensure code quality and consistency.
- Implemented Object-Oriented Design process.
- Utilized Git and GitHub.
- Developed in an Agile environment.
- Effectively coded design based on mock-ups and wire-frames utilizing CSS, Materialize, Bootstrap, and other front-end frameworks.
- Writing high quality, clean, reusable, and well-documented code.

#### ENTERPRISE CAR SHARE/RENT-A-CAR, Toronto, ON

Oct 2014 – July 2020

Enterprise offers carsharing services through two premier brands – Enterprise CarShare (U.S. and Canada) and Enterprise Car Club (U.K.).

#### **Branch Manager**

Accomplishments and successes highlighted to indicate value offered and a consistent focus on excellence.

Branch Manager – Enterprise Car Share		
Challenge	Due to staff shortages, we were unable to transfer a large number of vehicles to winter tires. External	
	vendor pricing was prohibitive.	
Solution	Sourced a mobile tire company that could deliver at a rate less than our service centre.	
Result	The swaps were accomplished at a lower rate and ensured staff were utilized for higher priority tasks.	

Branch Manager – Enterprise Car Share		
Challenge	Limited ability to service vehicles on the weekend as our service shop was closed. A vehicle that was	
	unavailable at the busiest time of the week was costly.	
Solution	Due to a relationship I had built and fostered with another shop, I worked out an arrangement with them	
	to service our vehicles on the weekend, or when our service centre was overwhelmed.	
Result	We experienced considerably less downtime over the weekend and more vehicles were available to our	
	customers.	

Branch Manager – Enterprise Car Share		
Challenge	In the highly competitive car-share market, we had to increase our presence across the city while reining in rental costs.	
Solution	Negotiated dozens of parking leases at below-market rates. Several spots were provided at no cost.	
Result	Our parking presence increased across the city, providing access to a broad geographical area to consumers while actually reducing monthly parking costs.	

Branch Manager – Enterprise Car Share		
Challenge	Undocumented damage costs were higher than expected.	
Solution	Implemented improved training and procedures for vehicle inspections, particularly with cargo vans which faced costly repairs. Implemented a video documentation procedure for staff usage for every vehicle inspection.	
Result	Undocumented damages were reduced by 60%.	

# **Jermaine Blake**

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (continued)

#### ENTERPRISE CAR SHARE/RENT-A-CAR, Toronto, ON

Oct 2014 - July 2020

Enterprise offers carsharing services through two premier brands – Enterprise CarShare (U.S. and Canada) and Enterprise Car Club (U.K.).

#### **Branch Manager**

- Developed Risk Management policies and processes to address loss, theft, and damage.
- Ensured team members took ownership of the need to address adverse incidents.
- Negotiated lease agreements in a highly competitive market with high-priced locations in Toronto.
- Developed partnerships and managed vendors and accounts.
- Conducted oversight for fleet management from maintenance and repair to recall projects, staff training and 3<sup>rd</sup> party, vendors.
- Ensured compliance with company policies and procedures and applicable legislation.
- Managed the branch Accounts Receivables and collections.

KIDS COLLEGE, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2013 - Mar 2014

**ESL Teacher** 

**CHUNGDHAM LEARNING,** Daegu, South Korea **Head ESL Instructor** 

Aug 2011 – Mar 2013

Won the Teacher of the Term Award

#### PASSIONS/INTERESTS

Sports, Music, Technology, Gaming, Science, Education

Football Coach, Camp Olympia